JIWON CHOE

(+1)713-906-2530 ♦ jiwon_choe@brown.edu 115 Waterman St. Providence, RI 02912, United States https://jiwon-choe.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My Ph.D. research focuses on the software and hardware co-design of concurrent data structures and data-intensive algorithms with near-data-processing. In order to fully deliver the benefits of new near-data-processing hardware with minimal architectural overhead, the data structures and algorithms must be carefully redesigned. While the data structures and algorithms exploit the features of new hardware and work around its limitations, they must also preserve the high concurrency and strong correctness guarantees of their counterparts on existing state-of-the-art architectures.

EDUCATION

Brown University, Providence, RI, USA

08/2016 - present

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

Sc.M. in Computer Science (05/2018)

Advisors: Professors Iris Bahar & Maurice Herlihy

Rice University, Houston, TX, USA

08/2009 - 05/2013

B.S.E.E. in Electrical Engineering, cum laude

B.A. in Computer Science, cum laude

PUBLICATIONS

Jiwon Choe, Amy Huang, Tali Moreshet, Maurice Herlihy, R. Iris Bahar.

Concurrent Data Structures with Near-Data-Processing: an Architecture-Aware Implementation. In 31st ACM Symposium on Parallelism in Algorithms and Architectures (SPAA 2019).

https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3323191

This empirical evaluation of NDP-based concurrent data structures provides insight into memory access patterns of data structures and identifies the minimal hardware support needed in the near-data compute units in order to increase throughput and reduce energy consumption.

Jiwon Choe, Tali Moreshet, R. Iris Bahar, Maurice Herlihy.

Attacking Memory-Hard scrypt with Near-Data-Processing (extended abstract). In *The International Symposium on Memory Systems* (MEMSYS 2019).

https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3357570

Memory-hard cryptographic functions exploit the non-trivial memory access costs of DRAM to hinder brute-force security attacks. This preliminary investigation focuses on scrypt, a widely used memory-hard key-derivation function, to look into how compute-capable memory may impact the security of such memory-hard functions.

OPEN SOURCE TOOLS

Brown-SMCSim: gem5 full-system simulator for near-data-processing

https://github.com/jiwon-choe/Brown-SMCSim

A gem5 full-system simulator that includes the architecture support and full software stack for near-data-processing. Extended from Azarkhish *et al.*'s SMCSim project. Used for evaluation in SPAA '19 and MEMSYS '19 papers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Oracle, Santa Clara, CA

07/2013 - 12/2015

Single Server Management - Hardware Management Pack

Developed cross-platform, cross-OS software for monitoring and maintaining the status of various hardware components on Oracle servers.

HONORS & AWARDS

2019 Best Student Presentation Award

The International Symposium on Memory Systems (MEMSYS 2019)

2018 Cadence Women in Tech Scholarship

\$5,000 award for women with strong academic record and leadership/passion in technology

- 2013 Tau Beta Pi, School of Engineering, Rice University
- 2012 Eta Kappa Nu, ECE Department, Rice University

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

ENGN 1630: Digital Electronics Systems Design

Brown University

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2019

Filled in for lectures; made problem sets and held several review sessions to help students prepare for exams; made and graded exam problems.

ELEC 220: Fundamentals of Computer Engineering

Rice University Spring 2011

Lab Assistant

Helped organize and proceed labs on: digital logic circuits and assembly language.

ELEC 241: Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering I

Rice University

Course Assistant

Fall 2011

Held weekly help sessions for problem sets on: time and frequency domain signal analysis, analog and digital signal processing, and signal transmission.

ELEC 242: Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering II

Rice University

Course Assistant

Spring 2012

Held weekly help sessions for problem sets on: basic electronic devices, circuits, and electromechanical systems.

CONFERENCE & WORKSHOP PRESENTATIONS

01/2020 Attacking Memory-Hard scrypt with Near-Data-Processing 2020 Boston Area Architecture Workshop

$10/2019\,$ Hybrid Skiplists: Combining the Best of Near-Data-Processing and Lock-Free Algorithms

Student Research Competition (at MICRO-52)

Career Workshop for Women and Minorities in Computer Architecture (at MICRO-52)

10/2019 Attacking Memory-Hard scrypt with Near-Data-Processing The International Symposium on Memory Systems (MEMSYS 2019)

Received the Best Student Presentation Award

06/2019 Concurrent Data Structures with Near-Data-Processing: an Architecture-Aware Implementation

31st ACM Symposium on Parallelism in Algorithms and Architectures (SPAA 2019)

01/2019 Hardware-Software Coordination for High-Performance Concurrent Data Structures with Near-Data-Processing

2019 Boston Area Architecture Workshop

01/2018 Managing Concurrent Data Structures with Processing-In-Memory 2018 Boston Area Architecture Workshop

10/2017 Managing Concurrent Data Structures with Processing-In-Memory Career Workshop for Women and Minorities in Computer Architecture (at MICRO-50)

TRAINING & DEVELOPMENT

Teaching Certificate Program: Reflective Teaching (Fall 2019)

Brown University Sheridan Center for Teaching & Learning

Completed four seminar modules designed to develop and refine fundamental teaching and assessment strategies and communication skills based on how students learn, as well as a teaching observation in a real classroom environment to receive constructive feedback on my teaching.

SERVICES

Mentoring

- Research Mentoring for Undergraduate & Master's Students (Summer 2017 present)
- Brown CS 1st Year Ph.D. Student Mentoring (Fall 2018 present)

Conference Volunteering

• Student Volunteer at ASPLOS 2019

Department Services

- Organizer for Brown CS New Graduate Student Orientation (Summer 2017)
- Student Volunteer for Brown CS Ph.D. Admissions Committee (01/2020)

Leadership Roles

- Vice President for Rhode Island Central Korean Church Young Adult Ministry (01/2018 12/2018)
- Treasurer for Rice IEEE Student Chapter (08/2012 05/2013)

Miscellaneous

• Volunteer Writer for techNeedle, a Korean online media for tech-related news (03/2014 - 04/2015)